<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Industrial Revolution on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/industrial-revolution/</link><description>Recent content in Industrial Revolution on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/industrial-revolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 2: Power and Economics</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/">part one of this series&lt;/a> I looked at how the evolution of tools is providing the ecosystem for creativity. In this part I look at how today’s changes in power and economics are also amplified echoes of the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="power">Power&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Power, Fuel, Energy. Your instant view on the meaning of these words is probably as much a product of the decade you attended high school as it is for any definition from the dictionary. If you are teen of the 70&amp;rsquo;s they probably bring images of coal mines, the 80’s oil refineries, 90’s renewables/wind farms and after the millennium, millions upon millions of mobile phone batteries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 1: Tools</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-goal">The Goal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this series of posts I am going to try to justify why I think we are entering a new age of technology. This is not about dreams, forecasts or predictions, it&amp;rsquo;s not about flying cars, telepathy or time travel, this is about what we can do today and how it shares striking parallels with our history allowing the many innovators to flourish due to the acts of a relative few. The historians among you will need to forgive me as I wield a poorly aimed keyboard through a house of stacked cards on the subject, however, the characteristics of the industrial revolution can be categorized into a few areas, namely tooling, power, economics and the daily life of a typical citizen of an industrialized country.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>