<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Storage on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/storage/</link><description>Recent content in Storage on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 13:00:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IT’s the way that you say it: The pitfalls of parlance</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have we allowed an obsession around priority setting to allow marketers to influence our judgement? It may be an early tangent, but think of how a traditional Western meal is described. It comprises a main element, usually a significant protein source, and then in another breath, the accompaniments. Has this approach of descending significance, when applied to an IT service, inadvertently degraded some technologies and solutions to be second class? Arguably, the larger proportion of healthy nutrition in a meal comes from the variety of complementary additions, as seen here from the &lt;a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-eating-plate/">Harvard School of Public Health&lt;/a>. Is it possible that when considering an IT service we could be over-signifying the importance of components?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 4 - or The Dead Parity Sketch</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-4-or-the-dead-parity-sketch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 10:09:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-4-or-the-dead-parity-sketch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In parts &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-or-from-disc-to-discovery/">one &lt;/a>&lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/">through &lt;/a>&lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-3-or-time-waits-for-no-wan/">three &lt;/a>of this series on the basics of storage we have covered off some of the fundamentals of the subject including why storage is important and made some headway into the terminology, in this post we look at some of the acronyms and initialisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="raid">RAID&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>RAID, has evolved its meaning over time from Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks to Redundant Array of Independent Disks, but its acceptable either way. RAID takes a few forms (known as levels) with the intention to provide virtualization of the underlying storage hardware to increase performance and protection for the data residing on a presentable logical storage device. The levels include&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 3 - or Time Waits For No WAN</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-3-or-time-waits-for-no-wan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-3-or-time-waits-for-no-wan/</guid><description>&lt;p>So far in this series we have looked at some of the social aspects of storage as well as starting our journey into the terminology that surrounds the storage industry – as we progress into part three, the terminology drops down a gear and races quickly to the speed of light.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="file-system">File System&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is generally a hierarchical structure and map between a human interpretable name, such as &lt;em>/home/glenn&lt;/em> and a set of stored data. This is the piece of software that knows how to find the data in your files. In most operating systems you lay down a file system as part of formatting a disk and there are lots of file system types, with some of the more common ones being ntfs, fat32, ext4 or hfs+.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 2 - or A Chip Off The Old Block</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 13:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-fundamentals">The Fundamentals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-or-from-disc-to-discovery/">part one of this series&lt;/a> we looked at how storage technologies play an important role in 21&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup> century human activity. As we progress further through the series we will look at more complicated subjects, along with some elegant, and not so elegant, architectural approaches to recognize and possibly avoid where possible. As for now, lets cover off some of the building blocks of storage architecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="disk">Disk&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start with let&amp;rsquo;s look at disk (or disc, they are interchangeable) – it&amp;rsquo;s what people generally think about when storage is mentioned, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a disk in your PC at home, your iPad on the move, or the enterprise storage array for the business critical application, the principle is the same, to store a copy of data that is persistent and easily accessible in a random fashion. The form it takes depends on the type of storage but it&amp;rsquo;s usually one of two types, one or more mechanical spinning disks (known as platters) combined to create a large capacity hard drive, or more recently the non-mechanical solid state storage built on a silicon substrate, commonly referred to as Flash or SSD, where performance and support for intensity of workload outweigh some limitations in potential lifespan. These issues are a little deep for the basics but suffice to say there is more to the deployment decisions than cost per GB, one of the subjects for a later post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 1 - or From Disc to Discovery</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="storage-made-simple">Storage made simple&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The goal of this series is to make the subject of Storage more accessible and give a simple explanation to some of those terms that you might have heard but you may not have considered in any depth. Also, along with other series of posts on this blog, look to provide some help in understanding the foundations of a number of the products that CSC take to market as offerings.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>