<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/</link><description>Recent content on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 20:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Echoes of Change: Enduring Legacies</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/echoes-of-change-enduring-legacies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 20:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/echoes-of-change-enduring-legacies/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I am covering the regular theme of memorable quotes from the world of entertainment and their (often tenuous) relationship to IT Services, I try to address it in a way that draws both humour and analogy in measures. There are a number of subjects that need only one side of this. I believe levity is essential under extreme pressure but it requires a level of true understanding, and with the advent of VE Day, I will only ever know the stories and will never walk the boomingly silent path of those who died, I will only ever know them by their words and the words of the survivors who walked with them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are you telling me that you built AI Innovation... out of a DeLorean?</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/ai-innovation-delorean/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 20:03:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/ai-innovation-delorean/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a leap back in time for me, I wanted to start a new with an old friend, the movie quote. When I re-read my take on &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman">Servers, Serendipidy and Superman&lt;/a> it seemed like a great idea to draw some parallels between the past and the future with another movie classic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a moment of cinematic history, etched into the collective consciousness of my generation (at least), where a bewildered quasi teenager uncovers an unexpected discovery. Michael J. Fox, as Marty McFly, utters a line that might just encapsulate a profound truth about innovation:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A New Chapter: Rediscovering the Joy of Writing</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/new-chapter-rediscovering-writing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 14:01:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/new-chapter-rediscovering-writing/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a new chapter, and I&amp;rsquo;m finding my footing again in this space, with the arrival of a new platform, and with the pagesetting and spelling expertise that AI brings (or pushes uncontrollably) into the mix, it makes some tasks easier and some harder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for the opportunity to have a fresh start, but also to a friend and colleague who took an extract of an old platform that has a number of old posts from the mid-2010s.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 10:01:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m Glenn, a passionate advocate for the power of storytelling and the beauty of simplicity in technology. Your visit here is appreciated. With a background (and foreground) in enterprise technology and a love for writing, I strive to create content that resonates as not only to fellow technologists but to anyone who is technocurious to bring subjects that can seem distant withn reach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I believe in the importance of clarity when the world seems obscure, and the joy of sharing experiences as a way to help others, whether related to technology or meeting some of life&amp;rsquo;s challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Days Before Cider</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/days-before-cider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 16:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/days-before-cider/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days are lovely, no clouds in the sky&lt;br>
I can see things for miles, from here, way up high&lt;/p>
&lt;p>sun bathing one day and drinking through straws&lt;br>
weighing down parents who are also in-laws&lt;/p>
&lt;p>now i’m the oldest my purpose is clear&lt;br>
i’ve done all my growing, my destiny near&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the leaves are all chanting, “go on, release!”&lt;br>
one day I will do, if only for peace&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it’s such a way down, with my vertigo&lt;br>
i’m jealous of others on branches so low&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving Statically</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/moving-statically/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 16:41:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/moving-statically/</guid><description>&lt;p>After yesterday being one of those days that achieving satisfaction seemed low down the list, today has provided
success in bounds, not least my $1500 overcharge with a car hire company got resolved, I won&amp;rsquo;t mention the name Although Vindicated I Should.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So with a bounce in my step, it felt like the right time to make the move from wordpress, not that I have a problem with the platform - it&amp;rsquo;s
that I love the idea of moving back to some cleaner interfaces, almost the same as a driver wanting to feel the road and feeling disapointment everytime
they get into a new car with power steering. There is an opporuntity at the moment to be retro and up to date at the same time, so while we have spent years
villifying text in favour of the hypnotic time consumer of font formatting - we can now get back to the idea that &amp;lsquo;content is king&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On servers, serendipity and Superman</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a fantastic line in the 1978 film &lt;em>Superman&lt;/em>, penned by Mario Puzo of &lt;em>Godfather&lt;/em> fame and delivered flawlessly by the actor Gene Hackman as the perfect nemesis, Lex Luthor:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Some people can read &lt;em>War and Peace&lt;/em> and come away thinking it’s a simple adventure story. Others can read the ingredients on a chewing gum wrapper and unlock the secrets of the universe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The line is profound, meaningful on many levels. It is in fact ironic to consider that 561,093 words might convey something of limited value to an audience and, conversely 35 words can inform and influence an entire generation. Thought-provoking as that may be, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering, how does that relate to any kind of technology perspective? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the idea that, just because there is an abundance of something, its sum may not have inherently greater value &amp;ndash; and let&amp;rsquo;s apply this consideration to lines of code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Server? What server? Becoming serverless</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/server-what-server-becoming-serverless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 21:19:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/server-what-server-becoming-serverless/</guid><description>&lt;p>Did you turn away from your terminal and miss Infrastructure as a Service? Well, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, as there is a new paradigm for the techno-hungry audience – and for a change, this one actually has something new about it! Most technology trends are re-manufactured from the last trend that did not gain the traction that its primary sponsors intended. When I say &amp;ldquo;new,&amp;rdquo; of course it&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;new new.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a way of working that is enabled by the confluence of existing technologies that have been packaged in such a way that its use can be widely adopted. Sometimes, working in IT reminds me of a great line from the TV show &amp;ldquo;The Big Bang Theory&amp;rdquo; in which Penny asks, &amp;ldquo;So what&amp;rsquo;s new in the world of physics?&amp;rdquo; To which Leonard simply replies, &amp;ldquo;Nothing.&amp;rdquo; However, being totally new is no strong measure of the potential for disruption, and this has some real potential for disrupting the way apps and microservices consume the infrastructure foundation of the Internet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Should our devices know when we're stressed?</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/should-our-devices-know-were-stressed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 16:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/should-our-devices-know-were-stressed/</guid><description>&lt;p>A couple of weeks ago, I was participating in one of CSC&amp;rsquo;s technology hangouts. The topic was around the shift to digital health. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FemiLadega">Femi Ladega&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanHushon">Dan Hushon&lt;/a> did a great job explaining the engagement between healthcare provider and patient on the care journey and the digital transformation occurring in this exciting field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the hangout, the conversation moved onto crowdchat where some awesome questions got posed and everyone did their best to make worthwhile contributions. In a conversation about whether patients would choose a physician based on digital capabilities, such as analytics for diagnosis, I raised a hypothetical voice instruction: &amp;ldquo;Hey Siri, take me to the best hospital for leg fractures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IT’s the way that you say it: The pitfalls of parlance</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have we allowed an obsession around priority setting to allow marketers to influence our judgement? It may be an early tangent, but think of how a traditional Western meal is described. It comprises a main element, usually a significant protein source, and then in another breath, the accompaniments. Has this approach of descending significance, when applied to an IT service, inadvertently degraded some technologies and solutions to be second class? Arguably, the larger proportion of healthy nutrition in a meal comes from the variety of complementary additions, as seen here from the &lt;a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-eating-plate/">Harvard School of Public Health&lt;/a>. Is it possible that when considering an IT service we could be over-signifying the importance of components?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sensors and Sensibility: The Internet of Things</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/sensors-and-sensibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 16:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/sensors-and-sensibility/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="buzzwords-of-warning">Buzzwords of warning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The IT industry thrives on buzzwords. It&amp;rsquo;s the industry&amp;rsquo;s fashion catwalk, and there are a large number of examples where existing products have been re-named to include and associate with a new trend. By far the biggest example in recent years is Cloud. In fact because the renaming was so rife, it generated its own buzzword: &amp;ldquo;Cloudwashing.&amp;rdquo; It would seem that any product or service that had a network connection was, in some way, a Cloud.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>'War Games' and umami: Pulling my boots on and walking the walk</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/war-games-and-umami-pulling-my-boots-on-and-walking-the-walk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/war-games-and-umami-pulling-my-boots-on-and-walking-the-walk/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my first blog in awhile, and the reason for the gap is one of the most interesting aspects of my job at CSC: the delivery challenge. As part of the governance team, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed core competency in asking questions and hearing the answers, sometimes despite the words spoken. A few times a year, I get to pull my boots on and go walk the walk.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-fresh-pair-of-eyes">&lt;strong>A Fresh Pair of Eyes&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The format of these engagements is fairly common. First is the discussion with the worried exec. This conversation covers the general area of concern &amp;ndash; for example the risk of missing a deadline, technology jitters, the need to inject innovation, etc. Second is the approach. With a reasonable problem statement in hand, this can be standard, too:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 3: Daily Life</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-3-daily-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:21:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-3-daily-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>In parts &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/">one&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/%22">two&lt;/a> of this series I have noted how the development of the industrial Web today bears some resemblance to the Industrial Revolution in the 18&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> and 19&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> centuries. In this final part of the series I look at daily life, community and contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>class Consumer { int money = 1; String product = &amp;ldquo;anything&amp;rdquo;; }&lt;code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Industrial Revolution, to a large degree, created consumer goods, or at least created a lot more consumers. Demand for goods excited the economy, which created jobs, which provided wages for men, women (and children) who were inspired to emulate their &amp;ldquo;social superiors&amp;rdquo; through the purchase of clothing and a wide variety of fashion accessories. (Pretending a class system didn&amp;rsquo;t exist would not accurately reflect the time.) Items that would have been grown or made at home, such as butter, milk, vegetables and lots of alcohol, were now available in shops. Today, the creation of the consumer class has expanded to encompass just about everyone on the planet. Virtually ubiquitous, although not equal, access to the Internet has been made possible through the recycling of handsets. Excluding yourself from this technowash is a lifestyle choice that raises eyebrows. We are now in a consumer world where the products are so vast in variety that it would seem everything has been invented &amp;ndash; until someone changes the surface to which today&amp;rsquo;s products are attached and we again need a new version of Tetris.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 2: Power and Economics</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/">part one of this series&lt;/a> I looked at how the evolution of tools is providing the ecosystem for creativity. In this part I look at how today’s changes in power and economics are also amplified echoes of the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="power">Power&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Power, Fuel, Energy. Your instant view on the meaning of these words is probably as much a product of the decade you attended high school as it is for any definition from the dictionary. If you are teen of the 70&amp;rsquo;s they probably bring images of coal mines, the 80’s oil refineries, 90’s renewables/wind farms and after the millennium, millions upon millions of mobile phone batteries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 1: Tools</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-goal">The Goal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this series of posts I am going to try to justify why I think we are entering a new age of technology. This is not about dreams, forecasts or predictions, it&amp;rsquo;s not about flying cars, telepathy or time travel, this is about what we can do today and how it shares striking parallels with our history allowing the many innovators to flourish due to the acts of a relative few. The historians among you will need to forgive me as I wield a poorly aimed keyboard through a house of stacked cards on the subject, however, the characteristics of the industrial revolution can be categorized into a few areas, namely tooling, power, economics and the daily life of a typical citizen of an industrialized country.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 5 - or DAS ist gut ja!</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-5-das-ist-gut-ja/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 15:18:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-5-das-ist-gut-ja/</guid><description>&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe we are at part 5 in this series already, hopefully for any newcomers to the subject you have been able to pick up some concepts and terminology, and for those with prior experience, a refresher in some areas. In this post we sign off from the basics by looking at a number of typical ways that data can be addressed from an infrastructure perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="block-storage">Block Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Disks and tapes are written in blocks of data to make it easily readable by machines, it&amp;rsquo;s the most primitive way of addressing the storage which makes it simple and predictable, so remains popular. In a lot of cases it is the right choice for applications that need an uninterrupted path to the raw data, this is usually because the intelligence for managing the integrity of the data is applied at a layer above, for example a relational database or platform specific file system. Using block storage can seem easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s a question of scalability of administration, managing a small number of volumes can be straightforward, managing 10000 volumes? Not such a walk in the park. Almost all storage systems ultimately use block storage as the means to store and retrieve data from a hard disk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 4 - or The Dead Parity Sketch</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-4-or-the-dead-parity-sketch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 10:09:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-4-or-the-dead-parity-sketch/</guid><description>&lt;p>In parts &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-or-from-disc-to-discovery/">one &lt;/a>&lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/">through &lt;/a>&lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-3-or-time-waits-for-no-wan/">three &lt;/a>of this series on the basics of storage we have covered off some of the fundamentals of the subject including why storage is important and made some headway into the terminology, in this post we look at some of the acronyms and initialisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="raid">RAID&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>RAID, has evolved its meaning over time from Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks to Redundant Array of Independent Disks, but its acceptable either way. RAID takes a few forms (known as levels) with the intention to provide virtualization of the underlying storage hardware to increase performance and protection for the data residing on a presentable logical storage device. The levels include&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 3 - or Time Waits For No WAN</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-3-or-time-waits-for-no-wan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-3-or-time-waits-for-no-wan/</guid><description>&lt;p>So far in this series we have looked at some of the social aspects of storage as well as starting our journey into the terminology that surrounds the storage industry – as we progress into part three, the terminology drops down a gear and races quickly to the speed of light.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="file-system">File System&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is generally a hierarchical structure and map between a human interpretable name, such as &lt;em>/home/glenn&lt;/em> and a set of stored data. This is the piece of software that knows how to find the data in your files. In most operating systems you lay down a file system as part of formatting a disk and there are lots of file system types, with some of the more common ones being ntfs, fat32, ext4 or hfs+.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 2 - or A Chip Off The Old Block</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 13:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-fundamentals">The Fundamentals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-or-from-disc-to-discovery/">part one of this series&lt;/a> we looked at how storage technologies play an important role in 21&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup> century human activity. As we progress further through the series we will look at more complicated subjects, along with some elegant, and not so elegant, architectural approaches to recognize and possibly avoid where possible. As for now, lets cover off some of the building blocks of storage architecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="disk">Disk&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start with let&amp;rsquo;s look at disk (or disc, they are interchangeable) – it&amp;rsquo;s what people generally think about when storage is mentioned, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a disk in your PC at home, your iPad on the move, or the enterprise storage array for the business critical application, the principle is the same, to store a copy of data that is persistent and easily accessible in a random fashion. The form it takes depends on the type of storage but it&amp;rsquo;s usually one of two types, one or more mechanical spinning disks (known as platters) combined to create a large capacity hard drive, or more recently the non-mechanical solid state storage built on a silicon substrate, commonly referred to as Flash or SSD, where performance and support for intensity of workload outweigh some limitations in potential lifespan. These issues are a little deep for the basics but suffice to say there is more to the deployment decisions than cost per GB, one of the subjects for a later post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 1 - or From Disc to Discovery</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="storage-made-simple">Storage made simple&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The goal of this series is to make the subject of Storage more accessible and give a simple explanation to some of those terms that you might have heard but you may not have considered in any depth. Also, along with other series of posts on this blog, look to provide some help in understanding the foundations of a number of the products that CSC take to market as offerings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 5 or When Milli and Micro Meet</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-5-or-when-milli-and-micro-meet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 13:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-5-or-when-milli-and-micro-meet/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part five in a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction, in earlier posts we discovered how containers fit into the IT ecosystem. In this final part we take a bit of a tangent and look at performance and how adding the next level of abstraction inherits and obscures performance characteristics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ok-who-invited-io-to-the-party">OK, who invited I/O to the party?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sharing of a CPU and Memory resources are low hanging fruit from a virtualization perspective, mostly due to their predictable nature in terms of performance, and to some degree the closed nature of the interface to the operating system leading to further stability. Adding I/O sharing and prioritization has always been a challenge, and can be a bit complicated, so let’s look at it all with the analogy of a restaurant – and bear with me, as you may get hungry during the explanation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 4 or The mental mettle to manage metal</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-4-the-mental-mettle-to-manage-metal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 13:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-4-the-mental-mettle-to-manage-metal/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part four in a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction, in the three previous posts we have set the scene for containers and covered off some of the impact on the wider IT ecosystem. In this post we look at how containers could affect your current environment and draw a close to this first series (almost…)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="do-i-need-bare-metal-servers-anymore">Do I need bare metal servers anymore?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There remains a market for bare metal in enterprises but it&amp;rsquo;s shrinking. The market remains for three primary reasons, maturity of the cloud, legacy applications and security. All things being equal there should be very few reasons that any next generation application would require a bare metal hardware platform. It is worth considering though that the bare metal market for another market segment is accelerating, namely ODM or ‘Other Device Manufacturers’ these are the firms which make the white box servers for some of the public cloud players and also provide the bare bones for functional appliances. Appliances in this context are self-contained purpose-specific combination of compute, storage and network. Recent appliances tend to be based around x64 compatible componentry as a lowest common denominator and widest development environment coverage platform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 3, or Rules are there to contain the fun</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-3-rules-are-there-to-contain-the-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 10:12:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-3-rules-are-there-to-contain-the-fun/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part three in a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction, in &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/">parts one&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-2-or-virtualization-is-dead-long-live-virtualization/">two&lt;/a> we looked at containers and how standardisation helps to build solid services. In this part we consider some of the wider implications on standards, security and licencing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="doesnt-it-feel-time-for-another-standard">Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it feel time for another standard?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well maybe yes, as we enter the next phase for abstraction we can execute on 4 C’s which expand out as the Commonality of Capability leads to Commoditization in Computing. As each abstraction layer is commoditized it allows the layer above to implement the ‘southbound’ layers in generic API type models, driving the further commoditization and common capability across providers. One of the interesting areas here, and why a standard may be needed, is how the abstracted component can advertise unique capabilities or services – take for example that a particular container or VM could offer certain scale-up features, or proximity to an existing dataset - would it not be of interest to the domain broker to be able to serve not just generic workload execution engines but ones that support the context of the business request? The open standards bodies that come together are clearly excited in this space – any subject that has a high level of cross technology magnetism such as Docker, will iteratively divide and unite the community very quickly, leaving what has been demonstrated in the past many times as the most generally acceptable solution to move forward, not always the best from a subjective viewpoint, but acceptable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 2, or Virtualization is dead, long live Virtualization!</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-2-virtualization-is-dead-long-live-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 17:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-2-virtualization-is-dead-long-live-virtualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part two of a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction. In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/">part one&lt;/a> we looked at the unsung hero in virtualization, the HAL, and in this part we dive a little deeper and scratch the surface on the potential benefits for applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="is-traditional-virtualization-dead-then">Is traditional virtualization dead, then?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We ended part one asking if containers are a traditional virtualization killer, and in my view they are both complementary and competitive. Sure, there will be some ground conceded, but it simply complies with the evolutionary process of what I call the &lt;em>absorption of differentiation into expectation&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 1, or One HAL of a Story</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 16:24:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part of a series of light reading points-of-view to help foster opinion on wide ranging technology topics, and maybe throw in some education along the way. In this series we are looking to provide some insight into the increasingly topical area of workload abstraction. As always, please feel free to comment and get in touch!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="how-virtualization-was-just-the-first-step">How virtualization was just the first step&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>So we all know where all this virtualization came from, right? It’s a common thought that the sole business case for virtualization was derived from the inefficient use of existing hardware resources, and of course this is part of the story. But the unsung hero of virtualization was the usage of a simplified set of resources from the hardware abstraction layer. This meant that when an application was running in a virtual machine there was a good chance that problems in the operating system were down to an exhausted resource or poor configuration, not down to a bad driver or a kernel fault. The combination of vendor testing and almost instant worldwide feedback created an ecosystem where any significant problems were either removed before release or patched before you had a chance to download it anyway! Not all problems were eradicated, but the reduction in variants at the hypervisor level created a far more standard environment in which operating systems and applications could live in relative harmony.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://glennaugustus.com/search/placeholder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/search/placeholder/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Comment Policy</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/comment-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/comment-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p>We welcome your contributions to the discussions on our articles and aim to create a space that is valuable and engaging for everyone. Our goal is to maintain a comment section free from spam, abuse, and disrespectful behavior, encouraging interaction between readers and writers and sparking stimulating conversations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To help us achieve this, we ask that you adhere to the following guidelines:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be Respectful and Constructive: Please treat others with courtesy and respect. Healthy debate and criticism of ideas are welcome, but personal attacks, insults, and any form of harassment directed towards other commenters or authors will not be tolerated. Remember that behind every screen is a person, and your words have an impact. Comments that are purely disruptive or add no value to the discussion may be removed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>{{/* form-contact action=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://formspree.io/me@glennaugustus.com%22">http://formspree.io/me@glennaugustus.com&amp;quot;&lt;/a> */}}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Test info&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>