<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SDN on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/sdn/</link><description>Recent content in SDN on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 10:12:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/sdn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 3, or Rules are there to contain the fun</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-3-rules-are-there-to-contain-the-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 10:12:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-3-rules-are-there-to-contain-the-fun/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part three in a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction, in &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/">parts one&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-2-or-virtualization-is-dead-long-live-virtualization/">two&lt;/a> we looked at containers and how standardisation helps to build solid services. In this part we consider some of the wider implications on standards, security and licencing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="doesnt-it-feel-time-for-another-standard">Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it feel time for another standard?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well maybe yes, as we enter the next phase for abstraction we can execute on 4 C’s which expand out as the Commonality of Capability leads to Commoditization in Computing. As each abstraction layer is commoditized it allows the layer above to implement the ‘southbound’ layers in generic API type models, driving the further commoditization and common capability across providers. One of the interesting areas here, and why a standard may be needed, is how the abstracted component can advertise unique capabilities or services – take for example that a particular container or VM could offer certain scale-up features, or proximity to an existing dataset - would it not be of interest to the domain broker to be able to serve not just generic workload execution engines but ones that support the context of the business request? The open standards bodies that come together are clearly excited in this space – any subject that has a high level of cross technology magnetism such as Docker, will iteratively divide and unite the community very quickly, leaving what has been demonstrated in the past many times as the most generally acceptable solution to move forward, not always the best from a subjective viewpoint, but acceptable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>