<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 20:03:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are you telling me that you built AI Innovation... out of a DeLorean?</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/ai-innovation-delorean/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 20:03:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/ai-innovation-delorean/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a leap back in time for me, I wanted to start a new with an old friend, the movie quote. When I re-read my take on &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman">Servers, Serendipidy and Superman&lt;/a> it seemed like a great idea to draw some parallels between the past and the future with another movie classic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a moment of cinematic history, etched into the collective consciousness of my generation (at least), where a bewildered quasi teenager uncovers an unexpected discovery. Michael J. Fox, as Marty McFly, utters a line that might just encapsulate a profound truth about innovation:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On servers, serendipity and Superman</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a fantastic line in the 1978 film &lt;em>Superman&lt;/em>, penned by Mario Puzo of &lt;em>Godfather&lt;/em> fame and delivered flawlessly by the actor Gene Hackman as the perfect nemesis, Lex Luthor:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Some people can read &lt;em>War and Peace&lt;/em> and come away thinking it’s a simple adventure story. Others can read the ingredients on a chewing gum wrapper and unlock the secrets of the universe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The line is profound, meaningful on many levels. It is in fact ironic to consider that 561,093 words might convey something of limited value to an audience and, conversely 35 words can inform and influence an entire generation. Thought-provoking as that may be, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering, how does that relate to any kind of technology perspective? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the idea that, just because there is an abundance of something, its sum may not have inherently greater value &amp;ndash; and let&amp;rsquo;s apply this consideration to lines of code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IT’s the way that you say it: The pitfalls of parlance</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have we allowed an obsession around priority setting to allow marketers to influence our judgement? It may be an early tangent, but think of how a traditional Western meal is described. It comprises a main element, usually a significant protein source, and then in another breath, the accompaniments. Has this approach of descending significance, when applied to an IT service, inadvertently degraded some technologies and solutions to be second class? Arguably, the larger proportion of healthy nutrition in a meal comes from the variety of complementary additions, as seen here from the &lt;a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-eating-plate/">Harvard School of Public Health&lt;/a>. Is it possible that when considering an IT service we could be over-signifying the importance of components?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 3: Daily Life</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-3-daily-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:21:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-3-daily-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>In parts &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/">one&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/%22">two&lt;/a> of this series I have noted how the development of the industrial Web today bears some resemblance to the Industrial Revolution in the 18&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> and 19&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> centuries. In this final part of the series I look at daily life, community and contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>class Consumer { int money = 1; String product = &amp;ldquo;anything&amp;rdquo;; }&lt;code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Industrial Revolution, to a large degree, created consumer goods, or at least created a lot more consumers. Demand for goods excited the economy, which created jobs, which provided wages for men, women (and children) who were inspired to emulate their &amp;ldquo;social superiors&amp;rdquo; through the purchase of clothing and a wide variety of fashion accessories. (Pretending a class system didn&amp;rsquo;t exist would not accurately reflect the time.) Items that would have been grown or made at home, such as butter, milk, vegetables and lots of alcohol, were now available in shops. Today, the creation of the consumer class has expanded to encompass just about everyone on the planet. Virtually ubiquitous, although not equal, access to the Internet has been made possible through the recycling of handsets. Excluding yourself from this technowash is a lifestyle choice that raises eyebrows. We are now in a consumer world where the products are so vast in variety that it would seem everything has been invented &amp;ndash; until someone changes the surface to which today&amp;rsquo;s products are attached and we again need a new version of Tetris.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 2: Power and Economics</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/">part one of this series&lt;/a> I looked at how the evolution of tools is providing the ecosystem for creativity. In this part I look at how today’s changes in power and economics are also amplified echoes of the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="power">Power&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Power, Fuel, Energy. Your instant view on the meaning of these words is probably as much a product of the decade you attended high school as it is for any definition from the dictionary. If you are teen of the 70&amp;rsquo;s they probably bring images of coal mines, the 80’s oil refineries, 90’s renewables/wind farms and after the millennium, millions upon millions of mobile phone batteries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 1: Tools</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-goal">The Goal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this series of posts I am going to try to justify why I think we are entering a new age of technology. This is not about dreams, forecasts or predictions, it&amp;rsquo;s not about flying cars, telepathy or time travel, this is about what we can do today and how it shares striking parallels with our history allowing the many innovators to flourish due to the acts of a relative few. The historians among you will need to forgive me as I wield a poorly aimed keyboard through a house of stacked cards on the subject, however, the characteristics of the industrial revolution can be categorized into a few areas, namely tooling, power, economics and the daily life of a typical citizen of an industrialized country.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 5 - or DAS ist gut ja!</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-5-das-ist-gut-ja/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 15:18:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-5-das-ist-gut-ja/</guid><description>&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe we are at part 5 in this series already, hopefully for any newcomers to the subject you have been able to pick up some concepts and terminology, and for those with prior experience, a refresher in some areas. In this post we sign off from the basics by looking at a number of typical ways that data can be addressed from an infrastructure perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="block-storage">Block Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Disks and tapes are written in blocks of data to make it easily readable by machines, it&amp;rsquo;s the most primitive way of addressing the storage which makes it simple and predictable, so remains popular. In a lot of cases it is the right choice for applications that need an uninterrupted path to the raw data, this is usually because the intelligence for managing the integrity of the data is applied at a layer above, for example a relational database or platform specific file system. Using block storage can seem easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s a question of scalability of administration, managing a small number of volumes can be straightforward, managing 10000 volumes? Not such a walk in the park. Almost all storage systems ultimately use block storage as the means to store and retrieve data from a hard disk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 1 - or From Disc to Discovery</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="storage-made-simple">Storage made simple&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The goal of this series is to make the subject of Storage more accessible and give a simple explanation to some of those terms that you might have heard but you may not have considered in any depth. Also, along with other series of posts on this blog, look to provide some help in understanding the foundations of a number of the products that CSC take to market as offerings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 4 or The mental mettle to manage metal</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-4-the-mental-mettle-to-manage-metal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 13:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-4-the-mental-mettle-to-manage-metal/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part four in a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction, in the three previous posts we have set the scene for containers and covered off some of the impact on the wider IT ecosystem. In this post we look at how containers could affect your current environment and draw a close to this first series (almost…)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="do-i-need-bare-metal-servers-anymore">Do I need bare metal servers anymore?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There remains a market for bare metal in enterprises but it&amp;rsquo;s shrinking. The market remains for three primary reasons, maturity of the cloud, legacy applications and security. All things being equal there should be very few reasons that any next generation application would require a bare metal hardware platform. It is worth considering though that the bare metal market for another market segment is accelerating, namely ODM or ‘Other Device Manufacturers’ these are the firms which make the white box servers for some of the public cloud players and also provide the bare bones for functional appliances. Appliances in this context are self-contained purpose-specific combination of compute, storage and network. Recent appliances tend to be based around x64 compatible componentry as a lowest common denominator and widest development environment coverage platform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 1, or One HAL of a Story</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 16:24:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-1-or-one-hal-of-a-story/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part of a series of light reading points-of-view to help foster opinion on wide ranging technology topics, and maybe throw in some education along the way. In this series we are looking to provide some insight into the increasingly topical area of workload abstraction. As always, please feel free to comment and get in touch!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="how-virtualization-was-just-the-first-step">How virtualization was just the first step&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>So we all know where all this virtualization came from, right? It’s a common thought that the sole business case for virtualization was derived from the inefficient use of existing hardware resources, and of course this is part of the story. But the unsung hero of virtualization was the usage of a simplified set of resources from the hardware abstraction layer. This meant that when an application was running in a virtual machine there was a good chance that problems in the operating system were down to an exhausted resource or poor configuration, not down to a bad driver or a kernel fault. The combination of vendor testing and almost instant worldwide feedback created an ecosystem where any significant problems were either removed before release or patched before you had a chance to download it anyway! Not all problems were eradicated, but the reduction in variants at the hypervisor level created a far more standard environment in which operating systems and applications could live in relative harmony.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>