<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basics on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/basics/</link><description>Recent content in Basics on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 13:48:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Storage Basics Part 2 - or A Chip Off The Old Block</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 13:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-2-or-a-chip-off-the-old-block/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-fundamentals">The Fundamentals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-or-from-disc-to-discovery/">part one of this series&lt;/a> we looked at how storage technologies play an important role in 21&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup> century human activity. As we progress further through the series we will look at more complicated subjects, along with some elegant, and not so elegant, architectural approaches to recognize and possibly avoid where possible. As for now, lets cover off some of the building blocks of storage architecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="disk">Disk&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start with let&amp;rsquo;s look at disk (or disc, they are interchangeable) – it&amp;rsquo;s what people generally think about when storage is mentioned, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a disk in your PC at home, your iPad on the move, or the enterprise storage array for the business critical application, the principle is the same, to store a copy of data that is persistent and easily accessible in a random fashion. The form it takes depends on the type of storage but it&amp;rsquo;s usually one of two types, one or more mechanical spinning disks (known as platters) combined to create a large capacity hard drive, or more recently the non-mechanical solid state storage built on a silicon substrate, commonly referred to as Flash or SSD, where performance and support for intensity of workload outweigh some limitations in potential lifespan. These issues are a little deep for the basics but suffice to say there is more to the deployment decisions than cost per GB, one of the subjects for a later post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage Basics Part 1 - or From Disc to Discovery</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-1-from-disc-to-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="storage-made-simple">Storage made simple&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The goal of this series is to make the subject of Storage more accessible and give a simple explanation to some of those terms that you might have heard but you may not have considered in any depth. Also, along with other series of posts on this blog, look to provide some help in understanding the foundations of a number of the products that CSC take to market as offerings.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>