<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Servers on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/servers/</link><description>Recent content in Servers on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/servers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On servers, serendipity and Superman</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/on-servers-serendipity-and-superman/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a fantastic line in the 1978 film &lt;em>Superman&lt;/em>, penned by Mario Puzo of &lt;em>Godfather&lt;/em> fame and delivered flawlessly by the actor Gene Hackman as the perfect nemesis, Lex Luthor:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Some people can read &lt;em>War and Peace&lt;/em> and come away thinking it’s a simple adventure story. Others can read the ingredients on a chewing gum wrapper and unlock the secrets of the universe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The line is profound, meaningful on many levels. It is in fact ironic to consider that 561,093 words might convey something of limited value to an audience and, conversely 35 words can inform and influence an entire generation. Thought-provoking as that may be, you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering, how does that relate to any kind of technology perspective? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the idea that, just because there is an abundance of something, its sum may not have inherently greater value &amp;ndash; and let&amp;rsquo;s apply this consideration to lines of code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IT’s the way that you say it: The pitfalls of parlance</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/its-the-way-that-you-say-it-the-pitfalls-of-parlance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have we allowed an obsession around priority setting to allow marketers to influence our judgement? It may be an early tangent, but think of how a traditional Western meal is described. It comprises a main element, usually a significant protein source, and then in another breath, the accompaniments. Has this approach of descending significance, when applied to an IT service, inadvertently degraded some technologies and solutions to be second class? Arguably, the larger proportion of healthy nutrition in a meal comes from the variety of complementary additions, as seen here from the &lt;a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-eating-plate/">Harvard School of Public Health&lt;/a>. Is it possible that when considering an IT service we could be over-signifying the importance of components?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>