<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/internet/</link><description>Recent content in Internet on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:21:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Industrial Webolution, Part 3: Daily Life</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-3-daily-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 13:21:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/the-industrial-webolution-part-3-daily-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>In parts &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-1-tools/">one&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://glennaugustus.com/posts/the-industrial-webolution-part-2-power-and-economics/%22">two&lt;/a> of this series I have noted how the development of the industrial Web today bears some resemblance to the Industrial Revolution in the 18&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> and 19&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> centuries. In this final part of the series I look at daily life, community and contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>class Consumer { int money = 1; String product = &amp;ldquo;anything&amp;rdquo;; }&lt;code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Industrial Revolution, to a large degree, created consumer goods, or at least created a lot more consumers. Demand for goods excited the economy, which created jobs, which provided wages for men, women (and children) who were inspired to emulate their &amp;ldquo;social superiors&amp;rdquo; through the purchase of clothing and a wide variety of fashion accessories. (Pretending a class system didn&amp;rsquo;t exist would not accurately reflect the time.) Items that would have been grown or made at home, such as butter, milk, vegetables and lots of alcohol, were now available in shops. Today, the creation of the consumer class has expanded to encompass just about everyone on the planet. Virtually ubiquitous, although not equal, access to the Internet has been made possible through the recycling of handsets. Excluding yourself from this technowash is a lifestyle choice that raises eyebrows. We are now in a consumer world where the products are so vast in variety that it would seem everything has been invented &amp;ndash; until someone changes the surface to which today&amp;rsquo;s products are attached and we again need a new version of Tetris.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>