<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portability on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/portability/</link><description>Recent content in Portability on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 13:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/portability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compute Workload Abstraction - Part 4 or The mental mettle to manage metal</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-4-the-mental-mettle-to-manage-metal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 13:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/compute-workload-abstraction-part-4-the-mental-mettle-to-manage-metal/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part four in a series exploring the topic of compute workload abstraction, in the three previous posts we have set the scene for containers and covered off some of the impact on the wider IT ecosystem. In this post we look at how containers could affect your current environment and draw a close to this first series (almost…)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="do-i-need-bare-metal-servers-anymore">Do I need bare metal servers anymore?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There remains a market for bare metal in enterprises but it&amp;rsquo;s shrinking. The market remains for three primary reasons, maturity of the cloud, legacy applications and security. All things being equal there should be very few reasons that any next generation application would require a bare metal hardware platform. It is worth considering though that the bare metal market for another market segment is accelerating, namely ODM or ‘Other Device Manufacturers’ these are the firms which make the white box servers for some of the public cloud players and also provide the bare bones for functional appliances. Appliances in this context are self-contained purpose-specific combination of compute, storage and network. Recent appliances tend to be based around x64 compatible componentry as a lowest common denominator and widest development environment coverage platform.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>