<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NAS on glennaugustus.com</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/tags/nas/</link><description>Recent content in NAS on glennaugustus.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 15:18:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glennaugustus.com/tags/nas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Storage Basics Part 5 - or DAS ist gut ja!</title><link>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-5-das-ist-gut-ja/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 15:18:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glennaugustus.com/post/storage-basics-part-5-das-ist-gut-ja/</guid><description>&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe we are at part 5 in this series already, hopefully for any newcomers to the subject you have been able to pick up some concepts and terminology, and for those with prior experience, a refresher in some areas. In this post we sign off from the basics by looking at a number of typical ways that data can be addressed from an infrastructure perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="block-storage">Block Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Disks and tapes are written in blocks of data to make it easily readable by machines, it&amp;rsquo;s the most primitive way of addressing the storage which makes it simple and predictable, so remains popular. In a lot of cases it is the right choice for applications that need an uninterrupted path to the raw data, this is usually because the intelligence for managing the integrity of the data is applied at a layer above, for example a relational database or platform specific file system. Using block storage can seem easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s a question of scalability of administration, managing a small number of volumes can be straightforward, managing 10000 volumes? Not such a walk in the park. Almost all storage systems ultimately use block storage as the means to store and retrieve data from a hard disk.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>